Music: Little People by Project Divinity
General forms are sculpted first at a low resolution
It's important to sculpt the general shapes at a low resolution to prevent unwanted lumpiness
The clay, draw, smooth, and grab brushes are good for this stage
Try to perfect the current resolution before sculpting at a higher resolution.
Save the small details for last
A textured brush isn't used because it lacks control over continuity and growth patterns of scales.
Flows of scales that contour underlying shapes are sculpted first.
Areas between these flows are patched with smaller scales that don't follow a pattern
A textured brush with are enabled allows multiple cuts to be made at once
The last step is to use a textured brush to give everything a bit of variety.