Here in the "Shapes" panel are all the symmetrical shapes for Sintel
we have 26 facial and 2 more for pupil dilation
while working on facial shapes
I found that working with "Texture Solid" shading enabled
which is in the "Property" shelf under "Display"
made it much nicer to work with
it gave me feedback on how our textures moved
and was close to what she looked like once rendered
once the jaw and eyelids are rigged and weighted
the first thing I do is to open the jaw
check and clean up the geometry inside the mouth
after that
I start creating a series of isolated shapes in full symmetrical form using "X Mirror" tool
I start with proportional editing
and then move onto editing individual vertex for final polishing
I like to work in symmetry
because it gives me the full effective in each shape
in the next section
you'll see how I break up the shapes to create a symmetry
on frame 220 you will notice that the only shape that I include in the rig is the screen shape
to create the shape
I first placed the eyelid rig and then built my screen shape around it
for each shape
I checked on three things which I call it Three Ms
first: "Motion"
I stare between default shape at all angles ensuring everything moves naturally
second: "Mixing"
since the goals to create shapes that are mixable
I mixed what I'm currently working on with other shapes
and that ensures that they blend well together
third: "Mouth Open"
for all mouth shapes
I open the jaw and make sure that each shape is smooth inside the mouth and against the teeth
the shapes might not look like much now
and that's because they're meant to be combined together
this layering method allows animators more flexibility to build more complex facial expression