Here we have all blended shapes connected to the facial rig
now ready for animation
at this stage I tested everything else but creating a series of quick and basic facial poses
which include a series of both bone names and emotions
each bones is keyed on every 10 frames
doing this text provides me with feedback on how well everything posed together overall
and ensures a good range that still looks pretty natural
since the shapes all now being controlled by the facial rig
animators use the controls to key poses
to speed up my workflow
I enable the AutoKey
OK let's add two more poses
one on frame 260
and the other one on frame 270
in the DopeSheet
default values have already been keyed
which allows me a blank canvas to start with
to create poses
I include jaw, eyelids and tone controls
but not till the end of the head, eye direction or pupil dilations
so let's hide these controls
now let's move on to frame 270 to create the pose
on frame 270 you can see how her face resets to default
saving default values every 10 frames ahead of time created a very quick and easy workflow
here I'm checking on the transition
it's moving smoothly and naturally
when working this closely to Sintel's face in perspective
I leave the camera lens to 90
switching the lens back to its default 35 creates an inaccurate distortion of the face
so I just leave it at 90
starting with basic symmetrical shapes seen in the full shapes tutorial portion
you can see how we can now achieve a nice range of a symmetrical movement in the face