The guardian required the shock specific facial expression which combines several shapes in one
here we have squinting of the eyes
the much corners are pulled down and out
the upper lip is pulled up and the lower lip is pulled down
and we also have the nasal sneer
for the brows here makes of mad, sad and raise up
to create the final overall effect of the blend shape
I also added the head, eyelids and jaw rig
here in the Property shelf
you can see the blend shape named "Death Face" at the full 100% value
because it's meant to be pushed to the extreme
the second version of the death face adds to the movement
in the Shape panel you can see the blend shapes which are now controlled by the rig
I also added coinciding shape for the inner mouth geometry