Hi, my name is Colin Levy, and my the director of project durian, aka(also known as) Sintel
I want to show you guys little bit by the structure of our ANI folder within our durian production repository
this is a .. the dirctory that isolate contain the dirctories of the project, and specifically
the animatic_edit.blend which is where the most updated version of the movie always was as you organize
so this is , right here, this is  the whole repository as you can see and  the biggest folder directory is
PRO nahz proproduction files, textures, models, scences
any exactly just mean the renders that's you know take up lots  space
so go into the any directory and you'll see this animatic_edit.blend which should open that up
sorry to open, ok , so here is the animatic_edit
and as you can see, it's a sequencer does it open
and the frame range goes from  0 to 21312, 21 thousands frames
so, as I described here, it's the entire movie
and, this is we currently looking at the color gray scence
so these up here, is where we can access all  the pre-scences in the file, basically every scence is like different sequence
it's basically an different editor or something
a lot of them has to do the exactly same things you looking at here, you know the final movie
this is the one, that we had set up the ColorGrading
but you'll see a couple of them, looks very similar, so if you goto the MASTER Edit
this has a lot more complex
as mine this, holy smokes, look at all these, you know , a lot of stuffs here