In some areas of the city
we want it to look like to be slum that have the junk everywhere
so rather than placing them manually
we are using physics scattered and found that would be a nice tool
that would be able to draw into the scene with grease pencil
and it will find the areas you would want the junk to go
and then use the script to place it
Er...
So I've got a group of objects here
of junk objects that are of the appeal
they are just proxy objects
you know really it would look good
alright
by the lines there the script...
It is working in progress and it doesn't do properly stacking
but it's quite quick
and it feels to me wagons' there I'm not sure about that
we can place them manually but that's hmm... What I've got so far
so far it is not quite rough and doesn't do proper intersections
We may add that later
use bullet or something like that
or you might just place it manually
because it is easily duplicate faces so we translate objects on the top of face
made it smoother so you can see the objects rather than the face getting in the way
but we can place them using snapping just kinda of what you can
OK use the face scale tool
so you gotta watch it
OK