Hello, this is Colin Levy
How are you
I thought I'll be interesting to do a series of really short and less than one-minute videos
to show you tips and tricks that I learned in blender during my time on Sintel
er I thought I knew blender
but apparently there's a lot of people who know a lot of things that I didn't know
everything in this little series gonna be simple, really simple
so to jump right in
first I wanna show you this in blender 2.5
let's say I have the scene open
and I want to make sure Anti-Aliasing is on
well, I'm gonna just scroll down all the way to Anti-Aliasing
wow that took about a second
but look how much faster it would be
if I could really quickly to close and open these little sections in the render panel
you can do that by hitting A
that just toggles them on
enough really simple
No.2: Math
apparently and maybe this is really obvious to anyone who has used this program
but you can do math in any field with their numbers in blender
so you've got 100 here
you'll just type /2
and it goes to 50
wow that is cool
now this is useful in a lot of situations
because if you're dealing with a technical things that have absolute values
so right here we've got this setup to be you know to render it 2000
what if you wanna render it in 4000
well normally I would come up with and launch the calculator
and do the math here that want it to be precise
but you can actually just type in *2 on both of these values
and there you go
beautiful
that applies basically everywhere in blender
No.3 Local View
also a feather from years ago that I did not know about
so basically when you're dealing with scenes of any complexity you're working in a space with a lot of other things
hitting period to center my selection
and sometimes to be a drag if these things are included in your view and the only one is selection of our objects
let's say that I want to get all the lights just by themselves
and it's pretty easy
first of all to select all in the same type with Shift G -> Type
and then go into local view by hitting the / button
Bam! Now all we see are lights
everything there was selected
and in a point you can just start working with these things by themselves
you can toggle in and out with /
and you can move things away from local view by hitting M
pretty cool
that's concludes the first installment of blender tips with Colin Levy