Hello
and welcome to the Blendr's Tips of Colin Levy Part 2
first I wanna show you is the special menu of light
so duplicating a couple of lights here
turning this one to spot
and gonna make a buffer shadow
now to focus this light
I normally go into here and change spot shape
and, you know, change Autoclip and...
but you can actually access these settings very quickly with the W key
to enter this Specials menu
so that you can change the spot size, the blend, so you can see
I'll rotate like this
clip start and end for shadows and and that's nice and handy, very fast
and it works specially for buffer shadow lamps
but you can also change the settings for all of them
so you notice that if you hit W key
this last feature called "Isolate Render Selection"
so I'm just gonna apologize right there
actually we've just forward in time two weeks
I am at home right now
basically I have to re-record the seonc part of this tutorial
because actually blender's functionality has changed
so I've got three lights here
and now if you hit the Specials menu
you will see that this feature has been updated
and no loger you'll have...
oh, I forgot what the term actually was
but now we have two updates here
Restrict Render Unselected and Clear All Restrict Render
er... confusing
so to see what's this does
let's open up the Outliner and set it to Same Types
what's this gonna do is everything in your scene that's of same types
whatever you have selected will show up here
in this case I got one lamp selected
so all the lamps gonna in the scene that are not selected gonna show up
when I change selection to this cube you'll see all the meshs of the objects
so here we go
we see three lamps here and
basically these features here make it very easy to isolate one of them or several to render
a lot of time you will be working on complex scenes
with ton of light all over the place
it's really important to be able to very quickly know what each of the individual light is doing
and fix, for example, shadow buffer issue with one of your lamps and if you don't want know which one it is
this is a quick way, sort of a test
so I've got one light selected
and I wanna see this light in the render all by itself
so by hitting W
the Specials menu
and going to the Restrict Render Unselected
that's going to look all of the objects in the same type
whatever isn't selected
it's gonna hide them from renderbility
so, as you see
now this is the only one that has the render icon toggled on
I mean other two lamps are off
and to restore it
you can go now to the W menu - Clear All Restrict Render
so everything is of the same type would now be renderable
and you can do this with multiple things of course
and that whould make this one to toggle off
now another related handy shortcut to hide objects that are selected remain renderable is Ctrl H
so let's say you have twenty-five lamps all over the place
and you want one of them to not render
so is the inverse situation
you can just selected and with your mouse just over the 3D view
Ctrl H
and you'll see the Outliner that the renderability icon is now off
and you can use Ctrl Alt H to bring it back
but you can, in this case, you can also just say Clear All Restrict Render
and it just will bring all back
and this is also useful for other thing than lights
but that would be the feature that was implemented for
and... it's really really handy
I used it a lot
and while we are here, one last thing
I wanna show this really cool feature
which you've probably known about
which is in the Sport Shape menu
a little toggle dragged down called Show Cone
so if you toggle that on you can now see in the 3D view where your lights are hidding
and that's really useful to know
a lot of time it's just hard to visualize
it's just really nice a little tool
OK. see you in Part 3