So this is actually one of my favourite little features
there is a way in Maya to do this
but now in blender
and so I asked Campbell
and he spent like 30 seconds running this feature
it is extremely exciting
so I'm going to duplicate this cube
and set up the parent, child
a little hot key here
basically all what I wanna be about to do is move along this chain
and so by using the bracket keys
you can now navigate through them
so cool
and you can even hit Shift and select, you know, multiple
and it's pretty smart the way it works
now I've got sort of a branch
this one is the parent of all of them
settled there
this is also the child of this parent
by hitting bracket right
it selects both
I'm not really sure how it will deal with the active one
probably the longer chain
in this case
it is incredibly useful and use it all time
you should
let's see
the other thing that I want show you is...
I'm gonna open up a particular dance shot from Durian
and so it's another Campbell feature
so, as you can see this is a pretty intense shot
if I enable all layers and holy smokes
what's is going on
I can barely see the scene
but if you look, hit the N key to open up this tab on the right
A to close this up
and under the Display tab
there's a Only Render option
what that will do is locate everything that doesn't render
rigs, cameras, empties, curves...  And make them disappeared under the view port
and wow look the clean that is
you can actually see what is going on
very handy
if you open up any files from the Durian repository
and you can't select things
that's why
so untoggle Only Render
anyway
awesome feature?
Part of 4 is next