So I'm just gonna load up Sintel
ans show you the coolest feature you've ever seen
But before that
I will show you Simplify
Simplify is in the Scene panel
And if you scroll to the bottom
You will see that what you can do by toggling on
It limits the view port the number of subdivision levels you are showing
So you can actually play back animations in real time
When you sort of simplify your scene
So if you look at Sintel
You turn down the Child Particles here
it just makes everything a lot more responsive
alright
so the thing I actually may have said about
that's really cool
but even cooler is
I select Sintel's body
going the Texture panel
And you will see one of the textures here is skin color
when you working in 3D
a lot of time you realize: "OK, I wanna make this changes on the texture."
then you gotta go into, Nautilus or the finder...or, you know, Windows Explorer
And navigate to where ever that texture is
To just open it
And this is a... You know, it takes time
now what we can do is just hover over this little file browser icon
and if you read the tool tip
it says "Hold Shift to open the file, Alt to browse containing directory"
How cool is that?
So, Alt click, the actual directory is just popped up
And Shift click, you'll actually get the image
Really really handy
I was so excited
Campbell, it's awesome
alright, on the Part 5.