Already
so, right now I gonna show you about the camera switching system that Campbell implemented for Durian
this, of course, as everything is subject to change as the most ideal system
but I found it's quite useful whereas here
you might want to know how to use it
so I've just opened up the cabin environment file
we've already got one camera
in here
by the way, while we are here
you can select the camera by going to set Select menu -> Select Camera
so now I've got it actually selected
but I'm gonna open up the Timeline
and the way that camera switching works is it's linked to markers
so I'm just gonna make a marker on frame 22
by hitting M with my mouse over the timeline
Now I'm going to create another camera
and just put it right in the middle of the scene
rotate it somewhere
not really the way I've played with the camera scale up and down
just for case
now we've got two cameras in the scene
and one marker
so, to bind a camera to a marker
and it is the process
you select the camera
you make it active by going in Ctrl 0
and in the View menu there is a menu item "Bind Camera to Markers"
so you've got this marker selected
and I just gotta do the shortcut Ctrl B
so now this camera is selected...er...active, that is
and you can tell whether it's active because this triangle above it is filled in
that is binded to that marder
now I'm gonna go forward to frame 95
hit M to add another marker
I'm gonna select this camera
go into with Ctrl NumPad 0
and, with my mouse over the timeline, hit Ctrl B
alright, so it's a little bit of a workflow you'll get used to
but, now we just grab
you will see how it switches around
you can move the marker to change the frame which camera will switch
you can re-order them
you can name them
and another is done actually in a really hacking way
by going into Frame menu actually just clicking here
"lalala..."
and... "shotA" like so
but this is how it's done for Durian, and it's really handy
I guess that's all we have yet for this one, thanks
er... a little addendum to that is
a little shortcut that compared that how it is useful
and that is Ctrl clicking on any of these markers, because they are bound, will select that camera
this is just a nice and easy way to access cameras in your scene
and another little thing is
if you make it unrenderable by, I usually go, Ctrl H
then it would not actually switch
so it is still technically bound
but when you play around the shadowing or other stuff
sometimes you actually don't want it to switch
or if you just wanna see what this camera sees, you know, for beyond and set up moving the frame that you've got
and you've decided on
you can just temporarily disable that render ability of that camera and enable it again once you want
this switched to actual linker
so, yep.