OK, so the next thing I wanna show you I'm just wanna pick up where I locked off
Is a pretty handy way of working with lights
So I'm just gonna add a spot light here
And since it's selected I'm going to go into it with Ctrl 0
And here we are
It looks as if we are in the camera view so you can do everything that you can normally do from a camera view
Namely, Fly
So Shift F is entering the fly mode
And from there you can point and, you know, aim your light
you can use R to rotate
or double R to sort of grab on something and look around
and if I just put the view here
and fold these stupid things
you can also see that the clipping plane that you've normally associated with the camera is the same thing as through the clip start and clip end
so if I...(I just bring it really low)...
You can actually see from within the camera view how much they like is able to shadow
and just that could be really useful when you need it to be precise
so ya, that's that
and one of the things that makes it a little bit annoying is
currently it's not really an easy way to get back to the camera view where you were
I think the previous version 2.49 you could do the same thing getting Ctrl 0
or something and get back to where you were
it's more like a toggle, maybe, I forgot what it's probably said
but if you're using camera markers
it's easy enough to Ctrl click and jump right back where you were
so that's another reason to use camera binding
Um... Let's see...
I think that's it
this is getting shorter
Bye