OK, welcome to Part 7
first thing I wanna show you is a really really simple
and that is when you want to return you 3D cursor to the origin
it's just a shortcut
but I have the want to do this, you know, for many many times
and I usually end up zooming away and go in like this to say
and then say "Cursor to Grid" to snap it
and that's just stupid
so what you can actually do is just go Shift C
and then your new cursor is on the origin
beautiful
alright, next thing I wanna show you is linkage
I guess it is also one of the pretty obvious things but I didn't know it
it's kinda convenient
I mean you probably find multiple cases where you wanna use this
let's just say, for example
I've got, you know, a camera with very specific, you know, lens size
and I want this camera and this camera to both have that lens size
what we can do is, select the two, select the active
hit Ctrl L, make links to the object data
and Bam!
Now they are all linked
and have the same attributes
you can do the same thing here
and for some reason I didn't know how to do that
it's quite useful
now what I wanna do is show you... Hmm... My driver is not mountains
so this is the way for the next Blender tips of Colin Levy