So to this tutorial
I'm gonna open up from the bamboo forest to talk for a time
and I'm just gonna show you how I set it up
how I will go about rendering other versions of this
because for the files you are gonna be digging through of Durian
basically, and now, I'm just gonna open it and hit F12
the things that should probably be done to make the initial rendering list
to render it quicker
so you can at least see... What the thing looks like
I'm just gonna go and turn the Simplify on
in the World settings there are the samples right there
and the Gather tab
24 would take a long time
so I'm just gonna divide this by 4 or 6
I just do 6
it's a really low samples
and then we can go and turn of Anti-Aliasing
turn off Ray Tracing... Well, we can keep that on
and for SSS, I don't we need it really in this case
check the render resolution
1024 is fine
and then hit F12
and a lot of times
SSS, you know, it should a side effect anyway
so if you are trying to judge the lighting in the environment
but you wanna see the character
you know, you can turn that off and do other things
just a bit of judges and renders quicker
so I just cut
when this render finishes and pick it up there
so here we are
the render is finished
and take about a minute and a half
so first let's put a view
and go into the node setup with Shift F3 to go to the Node view
and I'm just gonna change to the render compositing nodes
so, first I wanna show you how....er..  I'm gonna do it in the backdrop
you've probably known this
but, you know, a lot of time just there in the background
and you can get destructing it and you can turn it off
but to move it, you can go Alt MMB click and drag around
and a little bit more on the tricks than that is to scale it up and down
hit V
goes down, and back up
so it's kind of interesting
now another look
a quick thing I wanna show you is selecting the same type of node
for example
if you are not sure whether or not the focus is already on all of your render layers
because usually it will make sense to be at least on right one
you can hit Shift G
it will select the same type of node
wherever your curves you are set up
so you can see all your RGB curves
and you can even...er... If you got one selected
I think you can go to the next with Shift and bracket
so you can through toggles, through them
and then hit Home to view all
I thought that NumPad . Will take the center view
but of course it's not
now if you want to place or add new node
a lot of times I do is
I'm working in real close like this
I wanna add, say, a Blur
and, wow, it just appeared away, down here
that's not where I wanted
and I have to move it all the way back
and as I was wondering why it was
Barton just told me all I have to do is click where I want it
then add a node
and it pops up where you want it
so I guess you are placing an invisible 2D cursor or kind of the thing
and, it's just a little thing
it's probably handy to know
last thing I wanna show you right at this moment is
if you go to the image viewer and just click around
you will get this really handy...
We have to be viewing the render result
you will get this handy XYZ or RGB values here
so you can get some information about your image
what's alpha is zero, or what's black, you know
also, you can see values for Z
but even cooler than that is
you hit P
be here you'll have a very formal vector scope pop-up
and these are really awesome tools
really looks good if you expand them to the maximum
we can get some nice detail
and you can see the distributional color
these are the professional looking tools
so you should definitely use P in the image area
OK, that concludes this portion
see you later