OK, so I'd like to show you a couple of sequencer features for your quick
the first I just wanna do general file selection thing
so I'm gonna add an image sequence
just can navigate to this tab
whatever the sequence
what you can do is, actually, let's say these PNGs are mixed in with tons of various kinds of files
you can add... Do a *.png
and you will automatically select all of the files of that extension
that's really handy
a little thing
now here right now is actually the correct aspect create issue
a lot of times you bring something in
and it's completely distorted
so my first step usually is after I've imported something
to go to Strip -> Set Render Size
and what that's gonna do is
if you go to Shift F7
and look at dimensions
it's going to set the dimensions of the project to whatever that actually file is
so let's just say that comes in like this
I'm gonna go Strip -> Set Render Size
and as soon as you change the frame
you will see that is just set correctly
so now I'm gonna open up the aminatic edit
and just show you a really color balance stuff we are doing
and... gonna change the scene to ColorGrade
as so
these are referencing AVI files
and basically there is a really cool addon
which allows you to take any property of the given strip
and allow you to apply that same properties or values to other strips
and this is useful especially when you are doing color correction with the Color Balance tools here
they are pretty basic, but really nice to work with
and, so, let's just assume that I wanted to give this entire scene a really green fill
I wanna make it look like that
by the way, you can use Shift to make this ultra sensitive
what I'm going to do is going to the User Preference
Ctrl Alt U
and go to the Add-Ons pane
and I've already searched for "chart"
but we are looking indeed for the Property Chart
and you can just go ahead and enable it
and... (oops)
now at the bottom you would see the Property Chart
and it's already got all these properties enabled
the basic I would have done is
if I got this strip selected
use Color Balance
I can hover over a property like Lift
and take a look at with the Python line says "SequenceColorBalance.lift"
and you can see here that I've got "Use_color_balance.lift"
"color_balance.gamma"
"color_balance.gain"
so these are properties that I've just basically copy and paste into here
and that becomes what the chart is
so let's just say I want... Let's go ahead and make this green as we've designed
excellent that's perfect
now I wanna apply that to the rest of the scene
you see, as soon as I selected, the chart increases to the selection
and color balance is not enabled on this strip
the first thing I wanna do is make that enabled
now the gamma selection is changed
so this one his a slightly more green hue
and I'll just copy the gamma
so, right now, if you like this chart it's pretty normal
copy it over
and now the gamma is that green tint for the entire scene
that's pretty nifty
now if delete this actually right now I'm sure I'm having a bug with Property Chart
where it completely disappeared
but I could just say "color_saturation" I can just add that to the property chart
I'm undoing, so it doesn't disappeared
and say, I gonna type "color_saturation"
and I can see that saturation has replaced the color that we had before
so I can just make it completely this saturated
border selected these guys, and apply
now, saturation is down to 0 for the entire thing
so it's a pretty handy tool which I thought you should know about
so yep, that's it for this subside of blender tips with Colin Levy