So, I'm currently at home
I probably assume I'm gonna run out of the features to demonstrate
So it's just probably do a couple of more
But right I'm gonna show you a "projection editing"
Forget what the term it actually was
When I was under 2.49, there is a different way of doing this
this is really cool
this is basically the feature that allows you to take a base of geometry that has deformations
you know, it's not a plane
and you can take another object when you're editing the mesh that have the vertices automatically snap to the surfaces underneath
and it's really a great modeling tool
anyway, its approach in 2.5 is a little bit different
so I can either... Well, I just use this cube, since it's here
with Ctrl 2 just add a Subsurf modifier and make it smooth
so here we go
and I'm just gonna add a plane
and, basically...er... Rotate with double R
just because I want it to be outside
OK
so, basically we have to be in Shaded mode, I believe
and this tool actually is a snapping feature which makes sense
this feature was not immigrated in the snapping tools, I believe in 2.49
but here at the bottom of the 3D view
we can toggle on Snapping
and here right next to it is your snapping options
so let's click that
and go to Face
because it's gonna snap those vertices to the faces underneath
and, then, this is important to a magical button
right here
"Project vertices on the surface of other objects"
so just can toggle that on
we just wanna do
there, interesting
now I'm gonna prove that
alright, so I'm going to Edit Mode
hit G
and suddenly, as all we have to do, to need moving it
those four points have snapped to the surface of the object underneath
I need to just toggle Subsurf on more
so we can see, and, we're gonna subdivide to several times on this plane
we can always see it by then
now under Shade mode we can
and we're gonna press G again
and it's actually going to just confirm perfectly to the form of that sphere
beautiful
and you might be going like this
right now, it looks like it's still not doing it right
but if I change the view
you will see how it's actually deformed those points
so it's really a handy modeling tool
if you've got the shape of a model
that looks great, but the edge loops are not working
it is really a great way to start to work
anyway, that is that pretty cool feature, pretty easy, as well.