So, I'd like to show you guys
Basically, have a look at the animation at one of our files
And you can be really confusing
So, here opened a shot from the market scene "03.4b"
and this is what it looks like, fill it in this view and discover around
and track the cam
it's kind of collided
so I'm going to just turn on Only Render
so you can see what the shot is
so I'm just gonna put his view over here
and, so you got a 3D view added
and by going a Shift F6
and toggle on the Graph Editor
so as soon as you get there
you'll see one troop of vertical lines
and by pressing Shift and Middle mouse button
it's coming around
and see, yep, that's a lot here
and zoom in Ctrl + Middle Mouse or Mouse Wheel, anyway
there's a lot of stuff here
to full view of everything I'm now just gonna press Home
so, this is a lot of animation, and not all of it is even showing
but this is what the scene looks like
and if yo go over here
and press A, and then Numpad -
that collapse all the channels
now we can see, alright
we are looking animation for these two extra Man and Woman
the dragon, Sintel... No idea what that is
plus camera animation there are just a lot here
so we only wanna look at what are relevant to us
so let's focus on the baby dragon
I'm just gonna select baby dragon's rig
and you'll notice it's selected here, as well
and since it's selected here
I could just press V, and that should isolate everything to just what isn't been checked or selected in the channels here
so I've got three things selected
and I hit V
very directly
that should change what channels are available
I guess it's not working because I don't actually have the individual channels selected
but any case, actually the best way to do this is to turn onto this mouse cursor icon
and the tool tip is "Only include channels relating to selected objects and data"
so, you probably don't wanna see...I'm gonna press ++++
then A to select everything, then V, and you will see
OK, this is whole scene
you probably don't wanna see all that once
so I'm gonna press this mouse cursor icon
and that will do a really good job of everything is done
now you'll notice... I'll press Home here
actually there's nothing to show up
and this can be a bit of confusing
but the thing is, right now, we are not in Pose Mode
so I don't have the access to channels
and the channels are not selected apparently
so here we can just go in the 3D view
to Pose Mode, I'm gonna just use a shortcut Ctrl Tab
but you can also here to go Pose Mode
select all
and here we've got all of our channels
so these are all of the animation channels that have animations on them
wow, that's a lot
the tongue is animated
let's just go to the tongue
just select that channel, press V, everything else disappears
alright, so, it's not actually animated but their key frames are on it
the keys haven't to be identical
but I'm gonna look at all of it
so, pressing A here, and V, to show or toggle these ability
those of tools that are used£¬ A + Plus or Minus£¬V
or you can border select these channels, press V again, Home
these are all things that are  critical to use
and be able to navigate in, and figure out what you're looking at in terms of the animation
so, right now, I'm just gonna look at the "root", press Home again
and these are the animation on ¡°root"
what about the hips?
OK. So, it's moving pretty linearally and then we've got this channel, which is "X Quaterion", umm, you know, some rotation there
to look at... to select a channel...
uh... ok, first, really awesome, you can select all the keys to left and right of the playhead
with Ctrl + Right Click
so, I'm clicking on the right side here, and left side here, really really handy
and it's also the same in the DopeSheet
to select a channel, let me see how I did this
Ctrl Alt, and it will select all the keys, or, basically all the channels of those keys
you can also use the L key to select a single vertical of that curve
and then you're gonna select the rest of those it's connected to
and then, to select all the keys that happen on the same frame
just use Alt + Right Click to select
I remember in 2.49 there was there was the key which toggled vertical lines which is really handy
and this, sort of, gets back to that functionality
anyway, hope that would be a little bit of useful
while we are here, I'm just gonna show you really quickly on how to swap out the proxies
because, if you notice, I want you really note the left up here
and it's really chugging to play back
so, I'm gonna go back
first gonna turn Simplify to 0
play it back
so it does work better
but still, it's too slow
so what I'm actually gonna do, these are high resolution versions of the models we actually use in the rendering
but I'm just gonna swap it out for what the animation that is actually I'm working with
so I've got it selected, even through you can see, there is a Only Render
but I believe I didn't even have it selected
here we go. oops...
Dragon baby is selected
I wanna go over to the Object panel
and go down to Duplication
and you'll see "dragon_baby"
now I'm gonna select in this group
you'll see that we already have only two options
that is because the libraries are already owning it up
but here, all I'm gonna do is just to "dragon_baby_simpl"
as you'll see this disappears
but if frame forward, it snaps into position
and I'll do the same with Sintel
select Sintel here
so it is what she looks like
if I got the frame
she's got inherent stuff
we go here, the Duplication -> sintel_simple
frame forward, you'll see this is much better
now if I turn on Only Render
Ah, hahaha...
We recently turned off renderability for these guys
so, instead, I have to disable the rig layers
but there you go, it's much faster, it's still only 15 frames / sec
but instead, what layer this guy is on...
We don't need the extras
this guy is on this layer
so, start taking off layers, and....
There we go, we are playing in real time
so, hopefully that it is helpful in some way, and figuring out how to look at these files that being little overwhelmed
alright, see you in the next one.