Hey there
so, I think this is gonna have to be the last video tutorial in the series
I'm currently in Savannah
and tomorrow, actually, I'm flying to Amsterdam for the premier of Sintel
very excited, but school has started
and my schedule is filling up
I wasn't able to get too quite as much as I originally intended
but, I'm proud to see that you've made all the way through to No.12
and hopefully you found it useful
so, in the last tutorial, I was talking about animation
just how to visualize, how to look at the animation data in their files
and because it can actually be pretty challenging
just to see what's going on, you know, and to work with animation data you want to start getting into a little bit more complex scenes
and I wanna show you in this particular case
something that a little bit more of a test case
because it's a definitely outliner
here I've done the layout for the first scene
the scene was cut
this is the original fight scene that is gonna start of the movie with three bandies and Sintel
another rig has been updated since it's so... A little bit being broken her header's like lowing a bit
but from this part, she survives
and if you notice the actual length of the animation of this file, the single file is 1 min and 50 sec
so a lot of work, a lot of animation in this one file
and it can be difficult to, when you're actually working, to make sense at all
one of the limitations of blender, or just something so inherent about the way that blender works is that:
actions are properties of the object
so you can't have multiple objects in a single action
and this, you know, became a issue that little bit with, for example,
sintel's here, and actually all the bandies, all the characters are in this scene has stuffs
so, even a stuff changes his hands from one character to another
and part of change of setting that up is to constant the rigging side of it
but the other is managing the animation
when you have apended who has the stuff
what would normally happen if you have this "Only include channels..." button selected
and if you are working on the bandie's body
you see the bandie's body
when you working on the stuff, you only see the stuff
and, really, these things should be working in concert
because they are completely intergrated in, you know, the overall animation of the scene that's of any worth
but, you know, I was going to a process, just setting keys and animating
just really loosely
and, so, because I was struggling with just organizing the animation
I talked to AG online, and he implemented a little feature that I thought it was pretty obscure
I mean I don't imagine it that too many people know about it
and it's a button right here, if you are in the Dopesheet
"Only include channels from Objects in the specified Group"
so this is basically animation groups
and you can specify any group to, sort of, filter
what you are looking at in the Dopesheet
so, if I select Sintel's rig here
and I go into the Object buttons
you'll see in the groups, right here, that she is in several groups
and this one....both of them have this prefix "AN"
which is I just used to specify
OK, this group isn't animation group
"AN_ALLchars", so it's just characters and no cameras
and here, it's just Sintel by herself
so let me just show you all the animation first in the whole scene
and, just gonna select everything I don't know any to do that
alright, so, do you like the Dopesheet?
Summarily you get it pretty dense
and I can just scroll it down
lots of objects in the scene
if I toggle a few of these down
you know, this is, was....
actually, I was animating hands with empties for certain uses: camera, root of Sintel...
Let's see where are the bindies
anyway, I think you get the point
surely we have the bindies around here
"GEO-stuff" so you've got stuff separated from bandies' "jack_simple_proxy"
OK, so this is jack's animation
alright, so, it's not too bad
but, it's very easy to view overwhelmed
you know, especially for scrolling to all the stuff and camera are binded in it
and, if you notice the channel for Sintel's root is all the way up here
yep, Sintel's actual proxy and hand channels are where on here
and currently, there isn't a way to disorder them, can't click and drag
so, navigating and moving, you know, blocks of animation,you know, became extremely difficult to figure it out how to do
you know, I was working with the layers and not get a thing
so instead of talking isolate things
I'm gonna take use of groups, and use that to just help me
actually see what I'm doing
so, I'm just gonna toggle this on
I probably got one of these groups selected
but I'm gonna change it to Sintel
and then press Home
and now, our scene is animated, that I have determined is relevant to Sintel
so that includes Sintel's body, yep, here is all just the relevant animation
left hand, right hand, her weapon
and you know this is may not be as elegant as if all of these individual actions would actually one, unified
but for most purposes, it's already achieved that
and what next thing is I connected this boot of the view
and create another dopesheet with another group
so here let's look at "Smith"
"Simth" animation for example, currently
so we've got the root you're just translating his poses and stuff
and those are the three different objects needed animation
and because all here, the dopesheet icons
sort of, move all three of the same time without having to rearrange my view and find, OK, where is everything
so, ya, that is all I really want to share with you
and, just because, you know, being very very helpful especially with the scene which got very complex very fast
Umm.. Ya, I guess that is it.
If you want to send me... Or if you have very specific features or things you'd like to see demoed
I'm interested to continue this kind of short tutorial as here is
Um, but ya, I hope I find it useful
thanks very much for watching, bye